#### Kontakt

www.linkedin.com/in/michaelmüller-7190048a (LinkedIn) www.basicthinking.de/blog/author/ mmu/ (Rss)

### Top-Kenntnisse

Social Media

**Public Relations** 

Pressearbeit

### Languages

Türkisch (Elementary)

Deutsch (Native or Bilingual)

Englisch (Professional Working)

Französisch (Elementary)

#### Certifications

Social Selling Mastery 3.5 Certification

Digital Marketing & Leadership

#### Honors-Awards

PR Report Award 2019 - Best Campaign B2B

Deutscher Preis für Onlinekommunikation #DPOK 2020 -Best Campaign Industrial

Deutscher Preis für Onlinekommunikation #DPOK 2021 -Best Campaign Chemistry & Pharma

PR Report Award 2021 - Best Campaign B2B

Digital Communications Award 2021
- Best Campaign Storytelling

#### **Publications**

WhatsApp: Geliebt, gehasst, gelöscht.

Master-Thesis

Wieso Social-Media-Marketing ein schmaler Grat ist – und worauf es wirklich ankommt. Ein Leitfaden.

# Michael Müller

Heading InnoPR & Storytelling at SCHOTT | I'm a proud part of the #glasslovers movement.

Mainz

### Zusammenfassung

Innovations made of specialty glass are often small, require explanation, and are complicated high-tech. But they are always enabling things that change the world. As the thinnest, most flexible glass in next-gen smartphones, as a mirror substrate in the world's largest telescopes, or as a glass-ceramic cooktop in kitchens around the world: I translate new products into a broader, more emotional context. And I hope that this will strengthen the fascination for glass as a material in both the B2B and end-consumer environments. Current focus topics: Consumer Electronics, Living.

My professional background: I worked as a journalist for years (Head of broadband department @ onlinekosten.de; Tech-Blogger @ BASIC thinking) and consulted large international accounts such as SAP, Fujitsu, or Google, as a PR manager for FleishmanHillard.

My scientific background: Business & Economics (B.Sc. / University of Frankfurt), International Marketing & Management (M. Sc. / University of Mainz, Yeditepe University Istanbul).

## Berufserfahrung

**SCHOTT** 

5 Jahre 7 Monate

Head of Innovation PR & Storytelling

Mai 2021 - Present (1 Jahr)

Mainz, Rheinland-Pfalz, Deutschland

As #glasslovers, we have the most special relationship with the material glass. Let's translate this passion into exciting and engaging stories, told in all-new and progressive content formats.

Our comedy series THE RECEPTIONIST feat. Michael Kessler (watch here ⇒# www.schott.com/the-receptionist ♂#) marked the starting point for a Telekom vs. Internet: Wieso die DSL-Drosselung uns Freiheit nimmt und wir gemeinsam dagegen kämpfen müssen.

WhatsApp als Marketing- und Kommunikations-Instrument nutzen: Die kleine Revolution der Kundenansprache new facet of Innovation PR, focusing on emotion and entertainment. This Human to Human approach (H2H) adds a new layer to the communication of a traditionally B2B-focusing company like SCHOTT, keeping clear business goals in mind while telling the stories in a universal way easy to digest for everyone. Because we are all humans, no matter if part of a B2B or a B2C target group. It's a relevant, well-told story that matters.

We have just started (and are more than hungry to try out new stuff & reaching new heights)

PR & Communication Manager Oktober 2016 - Mai 2021 (4 Jahre 8 Monate)

[ENG] Innovations made of specialty glass are often small, require explanation and are complicated high-tech. But they are always enabling things that change the world. As the thinnest, most flexible cover glass in foldable phones, as a mirror substrate in the world's largest telescope (ESO's ELT), or as a CERAN glass-ceramic cooktop in kitchens around the world. I translate new products into a larger, more emotional context, strengthing the fascination for glass as a material in both B2B and end-consumer environments.

[GER] Innovationen aus Spezialglas sind oft kleinteilige, erklärungsbedürftige und komplizierte Hightech. Aber immer sind sie ein Kernelement in Dingen, die die Welt verändern. Als ultradünnes und flexibles Glas in Foldables, als Spiegelträger im größten Teleskop der Erde (ELT der ESO), oder als CERAN Glaskeramik-Kochfeld in den Küchen dieser Welt. In meiner Position bei SCHOTT (über)setze ich Produktneuheiten in einen größeren, emotionalen Kontext. Und hoffe dadurch sowohl im B2B- als auch im End-Consumer-Umfeld die Faszination für den Werkstoff Glas zu stärken.

BASIC thinking GmbH
Tech-Blogger
August 2012 - Oktober 2017 (5 Jahre 3 Monate)
Köln

[ENG] Subjective, opinion-charged work as a Tech Blogger for the commercial and popular German tech blog BASIC thinking. Writing articles concerning the topics Internet, Startups, Electronics, Smartphones and Computers. Published 4 out of the Top 10-articles of all time (1 / 2014).

[GER] Sehr persönliche Berichterstattung zu mehr oder weniger tagesaktuellen Themen. Was mich dabei reizt: der Kreativität sind kaum Page 2 of 4

Grenzen gesetzt - mein selbst erklärtes Ziel ist es, technische Themen stets unterhaltsam zu verpacken. Mein Steckenpferd bilden dabei Smartphones, Startups, sowie alles rund um das Internet. Im Januar 2014 war ich mit vier Artikeln in den Allzeit-Top10 des Blogs vertreten.

Eine Übersicht aller bisherigen Artikel ist hier zu finden: http://www.basicthinking.de/blog/author/mmu/

FleishmanHillard
2 Jahre 7 Monate

Senior Account Executive (Digital & Tech PR Consultant) Mai 2015 - Oktober 2016 (1 Jahr 6 Monate)

[ENG] PR consulting and support of various key accounts in the technology environment. Writing of press releases, media relations, event and project work including social media management. Customers include major key accounts from a wide range of industries, including consumer electronics, storage, appliances, software, business software / ERP / predictive analytics and security software.

[GER] PR-Beratung und -Betreuung von verschiedenen Key Accounts im Technologieumfeld. Verfassen von Pressemitteilungen, Media Relations, Event- und Projektarbeit inklusive Social Media Management. Zu den Kunden gehören große Key Accounts aus verschiedensten Branchen, darunter Consumer Electronics, Server, Storage, Appliances, Software, Business Software / ERP / Predictive Analytics und Security Software.

Account Executive
April 2014 - Mai 2015 (1 Jahr 2 Monate)

Johannes Gutenberg-Universität Mainz Hilfswissenschaftler (Research Assistant) Oktober 2009 - April 2014 (4 Jahre 7 Monate) Mainz

[ENG] 2nd Level Support, Account-Administration, Domain-Installation of workstations, Reparation of workstations, IP-configuration and coordination.

[GER] 2nd Level Support vor Ort und per E-Mail, Account-Administration (Active Directory), Domänen-Installation von Workstations, Reparaturen, Reklamationsabwicklung, IP-Konfiguration und -Koordination.

Onlinekosten.de

Ressortleiter Breitband (Department Manager, High-speed interner) Juni 2003 - August 2012 (9 Jahre 3 Monate) Hürth

[ENG] Department Manager "Broadband Internet" from 2005 (November) until the start of my studies in 2007. Self-organized writing of articles and reports. Taking care of the DSL Tariff-database and the background content, answering reader's mails, testing products (mostly smartphones).

[GER] Redakteur & Ressortleiter Breitband - tagesaktuelle Reportagen und Newsmeldungen über Entwicklungen im Internetzugangs-Sektor, Verantwortlich für Pflege der umfangreichen DSL-Tarifdatenbank. Zeitweise auch ressortübergreifende Artikel, vornehmlich zum Thema Elektronik / Hardware. Besondere Vorliebe für Smartphones, das iPhone sowie Produkttests.

# Ausbildung

Johannes Gutenberg-Universität Mainz

M. Sc, International Marketing & Management · (2011 - 2014)

Yeditepe Üniversitesi M. Sc., Economics · (2012 - 2012)

Johann Wolfgang Goethe-Universität Frankfurt am Main B. S, Business Administration · (2007 - 2010)